# Jorge García

Portfolio: <a href="https://jorest.github.io/">https://jorest.github.io/</a>

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-gamedev/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-gamedev/</a>

**Number**: +49 157 3617 6039



## **SUMMARY**

Curious Game Designer who is always learning more about video games and other forms of media. Experienced in creating games and diverse games and other projects using game engines. In previous roles, contributed to the making of games and experiences for different platforms. Passionate about XR, AI, and Gameplay. Currently in my last semester of MA Game Development and Research at Cologne Game Lab.

### **KEY SKILLS**

Game Design | Unity | UE4 | Source Control | Virtual Reality | Testing | QA |

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **UE4 Developer & Production, TriTrie Games**

11/2021- present

- Created virtual production settings with HTC Vive and UE4.
- Recorded mocap with Rokoko and Unreal Engine 4
- Created interfaces and game prototypes using Unity(C#)

## **Play-Tester, Giantdoor UG**

8/2021 - 10/2021

### Game: Derpy Conga

- Provided feedback and suggestions regarding game design and level design.
- Bug reporting and technical suggestions using tracking tools.

# **VR Software Engineer, TH Köln**

12/2020 - 03/2021

- Designed and scripted functionalities for an accessible VR environment (Unity 3D).
- Helped the project to come to fruition with positive feedback from the end-user.

# Game Programmer (internship), Universal Phoenix Group

06/2020 - 08/2020

- Programmed game mechanics for a tile-matching game.
- Generated time-based data, and stored it into binary files.

# **VR Developer, Optimus View**

03/2018- 10/2018

- Developed VR applications using Unity(C#) + Oculus to showcase real-estate properties.
- Optimized the projects to properly run in lower spec machines.

# Jr. Game Designer, Lion Works

03/2015 - 10/2015

• Game Designer for *El Chavo Playbook Acapulco*, a mobile game for infants.

#### **EDUCATION**

# M.A. Game Development and Research | 2020- Now

Cologne Game Lab of TH Köln

- 1. Modules included: History & Theory of Games, Game Programming(Unity C#).
- 2. Modules: Serious Games, Nonlinear Adaptation, Advanced Game Design.
- 3. Modules. Professionalization & Master Thesis Preparation

# **B.S. in Computer Science Engineering**

Universidad del Valle de Guatemala.

#### CERTIFICATES

# **Principles of Game Design**

Michigan's State University

# Game Design Foundations (1,2,3)

LinkedIn

#### LANGUAGES

English (Fluent) Spanish (Native) German (Beginner)

#### **OTHER INTERESTS**

I always enjoyed video games, music, animation, and fantasy. As I grow older, I become more and more interested in drama, mythology, and history. I am also a big fan of Tech news and pets (especially dogs). More recently, I got interested in cinematography and coffee brewing.